

Personal Profile

Xihui Liu is currently a Ph.D. student in Multimedia Lab (MMLab), the Chinese University of Hong Kong, supervised by Prof. Xiaogang Wang and Prof. Hongsheng Li. Before that, she received BS degree in Electronic Engineering from Tsinghua University in 2017. Her research interests are computer vision and deep learning.

Education

Multimedia Lab (MMLab), The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Hong Kong, China

PhD student in Computer Vision and Deep Learning GPA 3.925/4.0

August 2017-now

Tsinghua University

Beijing, China

B.S. in Electronic Engineering
GPA 91/100, ranking top 10%. Excellent graduation awardee.

August 2013-July 2017

University of Alberta

Alberta, Canada

Exchange student in Electrical and Computer Engineering GPA 4.0/4.0. National exchange scholarship awardee.

August 2016-December 2016

Publications

- Show, Tell and Discriminate: Image Captioning by Self-retrieval with Partially Labeled Data Xihui Liu, Hongsheng Li, Jing Shao, Dapeng Chen, Xiaogang Wang. European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2018.
- o Improving Deep Visual Representation for Person Re-identification by Global and Local Imagelanguage Association
 - Dapeng Chen, Hongsheng Li, **Xihui Liu**, Jing Shao, Xiaogang Wang. *European Conference on Computer Vision* (**ECCV**), 2018.
- HydraPlus-Net: Attentive Deep Features for Pedestrian Analysis
 Xihui Liu*, Haiyu Zhao*, Maoqing Tian, Lu Sheng, Jing Shao, Shuai Yi, Junjie Yan, Xiaogang Wang.
 - International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2017.
- o Orientation invariant feature embedding and spatial temporal regularization for vehicle reidentification
 - Zhongdao Wang, Luming Tang, **Xihui Liu**, Zhuliang Yao, Shuai Yi, Jing Shao, Junjie Yan, Shengjin Wang, Hongsheng Li, Xiaogang Wang.
 - International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2017.

Object Detection in Videos With Tubelet Proposal Networks
 Kai Kang, Hongsheng Li, Tong Xiao, Wanli Ouyang, Junjie Yan, Xihui Liu, Xiaogang Wang.

 IEEE Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017.

Working Experience

Sensetime Research

Beijing, China

Research Intern

September 2016-July 2017

- I worked with Dr. Jing Shao on person attribute recognition and large-scale image classification.
- Built efficient algorithms on real-time pedestrian attribute recognition in surveillance videos.
- Released a large-scale pedestrian attribute recognition dataset and published a paper in ICCV 2017.

Multimedia Lab(MMLab), The Chinese University of Hong Kong Hong Kong, China

Research Assistant

July 2016–August 2016

- I worked on object detection in videos with Dr. Kai Kang, supervised by Prof. Xiaogang Wang.
- Our team won ImageNet Video Object Detection Challenge with provided data, 2016.
- Published a paper on video object detection in CVPR 2017.

Teaching Experience

Teaching assistant of the following courses in The Chinese University of Hong Kong:

- ENGG5202, Pattern Recognition, Fall 2017.
- ENGG2450A, Probability and Statistics for Engineers, Spring 2018.